<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Haozhe XU</title>
    <link>http://www.haozhexu.me/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Haozhe XU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 20:27:58 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.haozhexu.me/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (4) The Wine Is Strong</title>
      <link>http://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/penfold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 20:27:58 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/penfold/</guid>
      <description>(4) The Wine Is Strong Penfold winery isn&amp;rsquo;t far from Adelaide city, the day was cloudy when we visited it, not a good day for taking selfies for tourists - I don&amp;rsquo;t usually take photos of landscape, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much to me. I brought GX85 with 12-35mm lens for convenience. When we arrived at Penfold, its signature red immediately attracted my eyes.
There wasn&amp;rsquo;t too many people in the winery, and the layout of buildings here is special, not sure how it was designed when it was built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (3) Slow City, Flying Life</title>
      <link>http://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 12:28:58 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/city/</guid>
      <description>(3) Slow City, Flying Life  Time doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly, life does.
 When we arrived at Adelaide city, it&amp;rsquo;s almost dark. We lived in a hotel opposite to the University of Adelaide. It&amp;rsquo;s not far from CBD, on the back there&amp;rsquo;s a street full of retailers.
I went out to the street with X-Pro2 and 35mm f2 lens, I&amp;rsquo;ve read people saying 50mm equivalent focal length is too narrow for today&amp;rsquo;s street, I think the key is to keep in mind what your lens could see, and look for things that can be framed, regardless of whether the street is narrow or wide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (2) Street on Island</title>
      <link>http://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/streetonisland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 09:26:43 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/streetonisland/</guid>
      <description>(2) Street on Island Kangaroo Island Kangaroo Island isn&amp;rsquo;t far from Adelaide, famous for its large number of scenery - actually I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether it&amp;rsquo;s famous or not, the only reason I said so, is because there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any ferry ticket available several weeks before we travel, so we had no choice but had to go with a tourist group. I guess they bought lots of tickets long time ago, in order to take their customers onto the island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (1) Lighthouse</title>
      <link>http://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/ontheway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 08:39:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/ontheway/</guid>
      <description>In my mind there are three types of travel, the first type is to travel with tourist group, visiting routine places and stay at each place for enough time to take photos (mostly selfies); The second type is more casual and relax, you have your own plan of where to visit and stay, how much time to be spent at each place; The last type isn&amp;rsquo;t just physically going to somewhere, it&amp;rsquo;s more about how one&amp;rsquo;s spirit evolve, like reading a book.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>