<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>camerareview on Haozhe XU</title>
    <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/tags/camerareview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in camerareview on Haozhe XU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 08:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.haozhexu.me/tags/camerareview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (4) The Other</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 08:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p4/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (4) The Other Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (3) The Color
Melbourne&amp;rsquo;s weather is very inconsistent, it was sunny midday, and now is pouring rain. I went into the library to make sure the camera still works when I return it. The huge amount of books in the library remind me of a quiz that I heard long time ago:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (3) The Color</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 08:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p3/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (3) The Color Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street
The first thing Leica feels to some people is a nostalgia feeling - it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to understand that Leica always reminds people of the history of photography; Usually, the second thing comes to people&amp;rsquo;s mind is its color signature. In film age, color mainly depends on film, whereas in digital age it would largely depends on the combination of sensor and firmware that converts sensor output to actual image file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 21:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p2/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) The Build
I could only use the M10-P for the weekend, unfortunately the weather was bad most of the time and I was afraid of using it even in light rain, I first thought this was because I have to return the camera to get my deposit back, but soon I realised even if it&amp;rsquo;s my own camera, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to risk it in rain consider how much it costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) The Build</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p1/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) First Seeing Recently Leica has some event that lets people try M10 for a day, I booked and when I arrived at the shop, the staff told me the person who borrowed M10 the day before had not returned it yet, instead I was offered an M10-P, which was a newer model that Leica just released.
It was the first time for me to use a Leica M, also the first time using a range finder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lumix GX9 - Dedication to Street Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewgx9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewgx9/</guid>
      <description>Lumix GX9 - Dedication to Street Photography  “For me, photography is not a means by which to create beautiful art, but a unique way of encountering genuine reality.” - Daido Moriyama
 My first mirrorless camera was a Panasonic Lumix GX7 which I bought more than three years ago, at that time I did not know anything about photography. When I was deciding which camera to buy, I only saw three facts: Mirrorless cameras from Panasonic and Olympus can share lens, there was a large number of lens to choose from, and, they were relatively cheaper compared to the ones from other systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>