<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Haozhe XU</title>
    <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Haozhe XU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 08:57:48 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haozhexu.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Metaphysical Study of Covid-19</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 17:03:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/covid19/</guid>
      <description>(Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not the right person to give any medical advice, see a doctor instead. This article is largely based on theories that are not proven by modern science, so please read it as a fiction if you want, do not draw any conclusion from it, and do not do anything based on this article.)
 The greatest enemy of knowledge is not ignorance; it is the illusion of knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift Study Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/swiftnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 13:30:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/swiftnotes/</guid>
      <description>Swift Study Notes The source of this file is available on Github where you can find the XCode playground file.
The generated markdown is currently used as a Hugo generated content hosted on my website haozhexu.me for better readability.
This is the playground I used during learning Swift, I mainly read The Swift Programming Language from Apple, took notes and wrote code as I read.
Soon I realised the notes could be organized in a way so that a human readable markdown could be generated with some tweaks, and I can even use Hugo to generate an HTML from it and host it somewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Summary of Networking in iOS</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 17:10:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/networking/</guid>
      <description>A Brief Summary of Networking in iOS I was reading materials regarding iOS networking and taking notes while reading, this article is a summary of all the materials I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far. It&amp;rsquo;s not a complete summary of networking or iOS, so you should not rely purely on this article to learn from scratch; However, having said this, you may find this article useful if you are already familiar with iOS and/or networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 14:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/javascript/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript Notes There are three ways of using JavaScript in HTML document.
External:
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- import JavaScript in head --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;index.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- import JavaScript in body --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;index.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; Internal:
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; // full form: &amp;lt;script type=&amp;#34;text/javascript&amp;#34;&amp;gt;  &amp;lt;!-- JavaScript code here --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; Inline:
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; function showAlert() { alert(&amp;#34;Clicked on a button!&amp;#34;) } &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;!-- display an alert on button click --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;input type=&amp;#34;button&amp;#34; value=&amp;#34;aButton&amp;#34; onclick=&amp;#34;alert(&amp;#39;Whats up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 11:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/html/</guid>
      <description>HTML Cheatsheet Basic components of HTML document:
&amp;lt;!DOCTYPE html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;html&amp;gt; &amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt; Specify W3C XHTML standard:
&amp;lt;html xmlns=&amp;#34;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&amp;#34;&amp;gt; Comments:
&amp;lt;!-- comments --&amp;gt; Inside head meta  &amp;lt;title&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/title&amp;gt;: name of the page, displayed on title bar, also used for bookmark &amp;lt;meta&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/meta&amp;gt;: provide extra information of this page, commonly used:  &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;keywords&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;key, word, tag&amp;quot;&amp;gt;: keyword tags of the page &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;description&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;: description &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;author&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;Author Name&amp;quot;&amp;gt;: author &amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;copyright&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;Copyright Info&amp;quot;&amp;gt;: copyright information &amp;lt;meta http_equiv=&amp;quot;Content-Type&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;text/html; charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;/&amp;gt;: encoding of the page &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt;: short form in HTML5 &amp;lt;meta http-equiv=&amp;quot;refresh&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;5;url=URL&amp;quot;&amp;gt;: redirect to URL after 5 seconds   note: &amp;lt;meta charset=&amp;quot;utf-8&amp;quot;&amp;gt; has to be put before title or other meta tags  style, script and link  style: used to define CSS style script: wrapping JavaScript code or import external JavaScript file link: import external CSS file  &amp;lt;head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;style type=&amp;#34;text/css&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/style&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link type=&amp;#34;text/css&amp;#34; rel=&amp;#34;stylesheet&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;css/index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 18:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/ruby/</guid>
      <description>Ruby Notes This is the notes I&amp;rsquo;ve taken while reading the book &amp;ldquo;The Well-Grounded Rubyist&amp;rdquo;, I tried to make it useful as a reference but do not expect this to be a well-written tutorial for beginners.
Basics
Objects, methods and local variables
Classes
Modules
Default object, scope and visibility
Control Flow
Built-in basics
Strings, symbols and other scalar objects
Collection and container objects
Enumerable and Enumerator
Regular Expression
File and IO</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/gitnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 11:36:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/gitnotes/</guid>
      <description>Git Notes Data in Git is like a set of snapshots of a mini filesystem, every commit is a snapshot of all the files at the moment, with reference stored for that snapsthot; Files that have not changed aren&amp;rsquo;t stored - instead just a link to the previous identical file that has been stored already.
 nearly every operation is local everything is check-summed (SHA-1) to ensure integrity most operations only add data to Git database  Three States Git has three main states for files:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Concise Method of Lottery Prediction</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2019/lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 15:39:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2019/lottery/</guid>
      <description>A Concise Method of Lottery Prediction  Q: The balls are randomly picked, how could you predict?
A: If so, why don&amp;rsquo;t people usually buy number combinations like 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6?
Q: That does not look random at all!
 In fact, the chance that the next lottery winning numbers are 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, is exactly the same as every other combination of numbers, but still, people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t usually buy number combinations which look like following certain pattern, and this is precisely how the algorithm works for prediting future winning numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Fuji Lens for Street Photography - 24mm F8 Body Cap Review</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2019/bestfujistreetlens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 21:09:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2019/bestfujistreetlens/</guid>
      <description>Best Fuji Lens for Street Photography - 24mm F8 Body Cap Review Human are always contradictory: we say we&amp;rsquo;d like to save the environment, while we generate lots of waste each day; We say we&amp;rsquo;d like to be healthy, while living in a unhealthy way of eating and working; We say we&amp;rsquo;d like to have a young heart, while becoming more and more realistic in a materialistic world…even when I escaped to the lonely island of street photography, there is also a contradiction: photographers say street photography is all about content while arguing about the image quality of gears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (4) The Other</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 08:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p4/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (4) The Other Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (3) The Color
Melbourne&amp;rsquo;s weather is very inconsistent, it was sunny midday, and now is pouring rain. I went into the library to make sure the camera still works when I return it. The huge amount of books in the library remind me of a quiz that I heard long time ago:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (3) The Color</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 08:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p3/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (3) The Color Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street
The first thing Leica feels to some people is a nostalgia feeling - it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to understand that Leica always reminds people of the history of photography; Usually, the second thing comes to people&amp;rsquo;s mind is its color signature. In film age, color mainly depends on film, whereas in digital age it would largely depends on the combination of sensor and firmware that converts sensor output to actual image file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 21:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p2/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) The Build
I could only use the M10-P for the weekend, unfortunately the weather was bad most of the time and I was afraid of using it even in light rain, I first thought this was because I have to return the camera to get my deposit back, but soon I realised even if it&amp;rsquo;s my own camera, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to risk it in rain consider how much it costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) The Build</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p1/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) First Seeing Recently Leica has some event that lets people try M10 for a day, I booked and when I arrived at the shop, the staff told me the person who borrowed M10 the day before had not returned it yet, instead I was offered an M10-P, which was a newer model that Leica just released.
It was the first time for me to use a Leica M, also the first time using a range finder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lumix GX9 - Dedication to Street Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewgx9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewgx9/</guid>
      <description>Lumix GX9 - Dedication to Street Photography  “For me, photography is not a means by which to create beautiful art, but a unique way of encountering genuine reality.” - Daido Moriyama
 My first mirrorless camera was a Panasonic Lumix GX7 which I bought more than three years ago, at that time I did not know anything about photography. When I was deciding which camera to buy, I only saw three facts: Mirrorless cameras from Panasonic and Olympus can share lens, there was a large number of lens to choose from, and, they were relatively cheaper compared to the ones from other systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (4) The Wine Is Strong</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/travelsa/sapenfold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 20:27:58 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/travelsa/sapenfold/</guid>
      <description>(4) The Wine Is Strong Penfold winery isn&amp;rsquo;t far from Adelaide city, the day was cloudy when we visited it, not a good day for taking selfies for tourists - I don&amp;rsquo;t usually take photos of landscape, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much to me. I brought GX85 with 12-35mm lens for convenience. When we arrived at Penfold, its signature red immediately attracted my eyes.
There wasn&amp;rsquo;t too many people in the winery, and the layout of buildings here is special, not sure how it was designed when it was built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (3) Slow City, Flying Life</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/travelsa/city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 12:28:58 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/travelsa/city/</guid>
      <description>(3) Slow City, Flying Life  Time doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly, life does.
 When we arrived at Adelaide city, it&amp;rsquo;s almost dark. We lived in a hotel opposite to the University of Adelaide. It&amp;rsquo;s not far from CBD, on the back there&amp;rsquo;s a street full of retailers.
I went out to the street with X-Pro2 and 35mm f2 lens, I&amp;rsquo;ve read people saying 50mm equivalent focal length is too narrow for today&amp;rsquo;s street, I think the key is to keep in mind what your lens could see, and look for things that can be framed, regardless of whether the street is narrow or wide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (2) Street on Island</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/travelsa/streetonisland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 09:26:43 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/travelsa/streetonisland/</guid>
      <description>(2) Street on Island Kangaroo Island Kangaroo Island isn&amp;rsquo;t far from Adelaide, famous for its large number of scenery - actually I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether it&amp;rsquo;s famous or not, the only reason I said so, is because there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any ferry ticket available several weeks before we travel, so we had no choice but had to go with a tourist group. I guess they bought lots of tickets long time ago, in order to take their customers onto the island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (1) Lighthouse</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/travelsa/ontheway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 08:39:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/travelsa/ontheway/</guid>
      <description>In my mind there are three types of travel, the first type is to travel with tourist group, visiting routine places and stay at each place for enough time to take photos (mostly selfies); The second type is more casual and relax, you have your own plan of where to visit and stay, how much time to be spent at each place; The last type isn&amp;rsquo;t just physically going to somewhere, it&amp;rsquo;s more about how one&amp;rsquo;s spirit evolve, like reading a book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/works/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 09:01:49 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/works/</guid>
      <description>My Works  Apps Published Books  Apps Below are my apps currently on AppStore:
Social Tagman Tired of typing #tags for different photos/contents on social media? Social Tagman is a manager for all your social tags, you can add and group often used social tags, selectively copy them with one click.

Ancient Names (Chinese) Randomly generate names (in Chinese) with strong ancient Chinese culture.

East Solitaire An ancient Chinese pebble chess game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 08:30:16 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Photo taken by a colleague at lunch time, I was using a piece of tissue to cover my face since I’m a shy guy who never wants to be in photos. Until I looked at the photo I didn’t realise that I wasn’t even in focus. Lesson learned from this: one’s not as important as he/she thought in other people’s eyes.
My name is Haozhe XU and I’m an iOS software developer currently based in Melbourne, Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
