<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Haozhe XU</title>
    <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Haozhe XU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 08:57:48 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.haozhexu.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (4) The Other</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 08:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p4/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (4) The Other Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (3) The Color
Melbourne&amp;rsquo;s weather is very inconsistent, it was sunny midday, and now is pouring rain. I went into the library to make sure the camera still works when I return it. The huge amount of books in the library remind me of a quiz that I heard long time ago:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (3) The Color</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 08:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p3/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (3) The Color Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street
The first thing Leica feels to some people is a nostalgia feeling - it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to understand that Leica always reminds people of the history of photography; Usually, the second thing comes to people&amp;rsquo;s mind is its color signature. In film age, color mainly depends on film, whereas in digital age it would largely depends on the combination of sensor and firmware that converts sensor output to actual image file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 21:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p2/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) The Build
I could only use the M10-P for the weekend, unfortunately the weather was bad most of the time and I was afraid of using it even in light rain, I first thought this was because I have to return the camera to get my deposit back, but soon I realised even if it&amp;rsquo;s my own camera, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to risk it in rain consider how much it costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) The Build</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p1/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) First Seeing Recently Leica has some event that lets people try M10 for a day, I booked and when I arrived at the shop, the staff told me the person who borrowed M10 the day before had not returned it yet, instead I was offered an M10-P, which was a newer model that Leica just released.
It was the first time for me to use a Leica M, also the first time using a range finder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lumix GX9 - Dedication to Street Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewgx9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewgx9/</guid>
      <description>Lumix GX9 - Dedication to Street Photography  “For me, photography is not a means by which to create beautiful art, but a unique way of encountering genuine reality.” - Daido Moriyama
 My first mirrorless camera was a Panasonic Lumix GX7 which I bought more than three years ago, at that time I did not know anything about photography. When I was deciding which camera to buy, I only saw three facts: Mirrorless cameras from Panasonic and Olympus can share lens, there was a large number of lens to choose from, and, they were relatively cheaper compared to the ones from other systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (4) The Wine Is Strong</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/penfold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 20:27:58 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/penfold/</guid>
      <description>(4) The Wine Is Strong Penfold winery isn&amp;rsquo;t far from Adelaide city, the day was cloudy when we visited it, not a good day for taking selfies for tourists - I don&amp;rsquo;t usually take photos of landscape, so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter too much to me. I brought GX85 with 12-35mm lens for convenience. When we arrived at Penfold, its signature red immediately attracted my eyes.
There wasn&amp;rsquo;t too many people in the winery, and the layout of buildings here is special, not sure how it was designed when it was built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (3) Slow City, Flying Life</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 12:28:58 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/city/</guid>
      <description>(3) Slow City, Flying Life  Time doesn&amp;rsquo;t fly, life does.
 When we arrived at Adelaide city, it&amp;rsquo;s almost dark. We lived in a hotel opposite to the University of Adelaide. It&amp;rsquo;s not far from CBD, on the back there&amp;rsquo;s a street full of retailers.
I went out to the street with X-Pro2 and 35mm f2 lens, I&amp;rsquo;ve read people saying 50mm equivalent focal length is too narrow for today&amp;rsquo;s street, I think the key is to keep in mind what your lens could see, and look for things that can be framed, regardless of whether the street is narrow or wide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (2) Street on Island</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/streetonisland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 09:26:43 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/streetonisland/</guid>
      <description>(2) Street on Island Kangaroo Island Kangaroo Island isn&amp;rsquo;t far from Adelaide, famous for its large number of scenery - actually I don&amp;rsquo;t know whether it&amp;rsquo;s famous or not, the only reason I said so, is because there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any ferry ticket available several weeks before we travel, so we had no choice but had to go with a tourist group. I guess they bought lots of tickets long time ago, in order to take their customers onto the island.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (1) Lighthouse</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/ontheway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 08:39:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/ontheway/</guid>
      <description>In my mind there are three types of travel, the first type is to travel with tourist group, visiting routine places and stay at each place for enough time to take photos (mostly selfies); The second type is more casual and relax, you have your own plan of where to visit and stay, how much time to be spent at each place; The last type isn&amp;rsquo;t just physically going to somewhere, it&amp;rsquo;s more about how one&amp;rsquo;s spirit evolve, like reading a book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pseudo Science - Prologue</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/pseudo_science/prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 07:23:49 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/pseudo_science/prologue/</guid>
      <description>Rediscover the Wonderful World with Pseudo-Science Prologue I was on the flight back to China, the air conditioner made me feel sick, it was a bit too cold. I tried to focus on something that could distract me from the sickness, then I noticed the small round window next to me, it reminded me of the windows in the classroom of my elementary school — they have wooden frames painted in green and are always clean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 09:01:49 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/apps/</guid>
      <description>Below are my apps currently on AppStore:
Social Tagman Tired of typing #tags for different photos/contents on social media? Social Tagman is a manager for all your social tags, you can add and group often used social tags, selectively copy them with one click.

Ancient Names (Chinese) Randomly generate names (in Chinese) with strong ancient Chinese culture.

East Solitaire An ancient Chinese pebble chess game.

I&amp;rsquo;m Sucker An app that generates poems following ancient Chinese poetry pattern and style, with random intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 08:30:16 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Photo taken by a colleague at lunch time, I was using a piece of tissue to cover my face since I’m a shy guy who never wants to be in photos. Until I looked at the photo I didn’t realise that I wasn’t even in focus. Lesson learned from this: one’s not as important as he/she thought in other people’s eyes.
My name is Haozhe XU and I’m an iOS software developer currently based in Melbourne, Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>