<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>streetphotography on Haozhe XU</title>
    <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/tags/streetphotography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in streetphotography on Haozhe XU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 21:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.haozhexu.me/tags/streetphotography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 21:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p2/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (2) The Street Previous: 100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) The Build
I could only use the M10-P for the weekend, unfortunately the weather was bad most of the time and I was afraid of using it even in light rain, I first thought this was because I have to return the camera to get my deposit back, but soon I realised even if it&#39;s my own camera, I wouldn&#39;t want to risk it in rain consider how much it costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) The Build</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewleicam10p1/</guid>
      <description>100 Years in One Day - Leica M10-P Review (1) First Seeing Recently Leica has some event that lets people try M10 for a day, I booked and when I arrived at the shop, the staff told me the person who borrowed M10 the day before had not returned it yet, instead I was offered an M10-P, which was a newer model that Leica just released.
It was the first time for me to use a Leica M, also the first time using a range finder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lumix GX9 - Dedication to Street Photography</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewgx9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2018/reviewgx9/</guid>
      <description>Lumix GX9 - Dedication to Street Photography  “For me, photography is not a means by which to create beautiful art, but a unique way of encountering genuine reality.” - Daido Moriyama
 My first mirrorless camera was a Panasonic Lumix GX7 which I bought more than three years ago, at that time I did not know anything about photography. When I was deciding which camera to buy, I only saw three facts: Mirrorless cameras from Panasonic and Olympus can share lens, there was a large number of lens to choose from, and, they were relatively cheaper compared to the ones from other systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (3) Slow City, Flying Life</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 12:28:58 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/city/</guid>
      <description>(3) Slow City, Flying Life  Time doesn&#39;t fly, life does.
 When we arrived at Adelaide city, it&#39;s almost dark. We lived in a hotel opposite to the University of Adelaide. It&#39;s not far from CBD, on the back there&#39;s a street full of retailers.
I went out to the street with X-Pro2 and 35mm f2 lens, I&#39;ve read people saying 50mm equivalent focal length is too narrow for today&#39;s street, I think the key is to keep in mind what your lens could see, and look for things that can be framed, regardless of whether the street is narrow or wide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If life is always like first seeing - Adelaide (2) Street on Island</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/streetonisland/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 09:26:43 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/travelphotographysa/streetonisland/</guid>
      <description>(2) Street on Island Kangaroo Island Kangaroo Island isn&#39;t far from Adelaide, famous for its large number of scenery - actually I don&#39;t know whether it&#39;s famous or not, the only reason I said so, is because there wasn&#39;t any ferry ticket available several weeks before we travel, so we had no choice but had to go with a tourist group. I guess they bought lots of tickets long time ago, in order to take their customers onto the island.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>