<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Article on Haozhe XU</title>
    <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/categories/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Article on Haozhe XU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 17:03:36 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.haozhexu.me/categories/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Metaphysical Study of Covid-19</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 17:03:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2020/covid19/</guid>
      <description>(Disclaimer: I&amp;rsquo;m not the right person to give any medical advice, see a doctor instead. This article is largely based on theories that are not proven by modern science, so please read it as a fiction if you want, do not draw any conclusion from it, and do not do anything based on this article.)
 The greatest enemy of knowledge is not ignorance; it is the illusion of knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Concise Method of Lottery Prediction</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2019/lottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 15:39:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/2019/lottery/</guid>
      <description>A Concise Method of Lottery Prediction  Q: The balls are randomly picked, how could you predict?
A: If so, why don&amp;rsquo;t people usually buy number combinations like 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6?
Q: That does not look random at all!
 In fact, the chance that the next lottery winning numbers are 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, is exactly the same as every other combination of numbers, but still, people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t usually buy number combinations which look like following certain pattern, and this is precisely how the algorithm works for prediting future winning numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaphysics - The Moon (2)</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/pseudo_science/chapter2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 08:17:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/pseudo_science/chapter2/</guid>
      <description>Rediscover the Wonderful World with Metaphysics The Moon (2)  This thing is massive…
We&amp;rsquo;re not alone, are we?
No sir. We are not alone.
 Transformer: Dark of the Moon   Transformers: Dark of the Moon is a 2011 American science fiction/action film in the Transformers film series, in the beginning of the movie, astronauts found transformers on the back (ie. dark) side of the moon. Although the film is full of fictional elements, this particular plot has a deep background.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaphysics - The Moon (1)</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/pseudo_science/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 09:03:36 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/pseudo_science/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>Rediscover the Wonderful World with Metaphysics The Moon (1)  How rare the moon, so round and clear!
With cup in hand, I ask of the blue sky,
&amp;ldquo;I do not know in the celestial sphere
What name this festive night goes by?&amp;rdquo;
Su Shi, Chinese Poem
 I once had a long dream, in the dream I was invited to a meeting and the meeting took place inside the Pyramid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaphysics - Prologue</title>
      <link>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/pseudo_science/prologue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 08:01:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.haozhexu.me/article/pseudo_science/prologue/</guid>
      <description>Rediscover the Wonderful World with Metaphysics Prologue Every year I fly back to China to visit my relatives, many years ago, when I was on the plane back to China, the air conditioning was bit too aggressive which made me uncomfortable, I tried to find something to divert my attention and then noticed the small round window next to me, it reminds me of the windows in the classroom of my elementary school, with green wooden window frame.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>